(
"ai_sub_version": "3.6.0",
"generated_at": "2026-10-09T22:30:07.055390",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"service_tier": null,
"service_tier_subtitles": null,
"service_tier_lyrics": null,
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
Departure!
Composition: 羽場仁志 • Lyrics: 羽場仁志, TEAM HUNTER
Composition: Hitoshi Haba • Lyrics: Hitoshi Haba, TEAM HUNTER
大地を踏みしめて
Step firmly onto the earth
君は目覚めていく
as you begin to awaken.
天使の微笑みで
With an angel's smile,
連れ出して!
take me away!
孤独でも
Even in loneliness,
一人じゃないさ
you are not alone.
生まれてきたことに
There is always a meaning
必ず意味がある
in being born into this world.
優しさに
It is overflowing
満ち溢れてる
with kindness.
青い星にありがとう
Thank you to the blue planet.
You can smile again
太陽浴びて
bathing in the sun's rays.
You can fly away
世界は君の
The world is waiting
輝きを待ってる
for your shine.
大地を踏みしめて
Step firmly onto the earth
君は目覚めていく
as you begin to awaken.
天使の微笑みで
With an angel's smile,
連れ出して!
take me away!
始まりはいつでも
A new beginning is always
遅くないさ
never too late.
何度でも立ち上がれ!
Rise up, time and time again!
最後まで
Until the very end,
あきらめないさ
I won't give up!
やり続けることに
There is always a meaning
必ず意味がある
in continuing to try.
You just try again
闇を抜けて
Break through the darkness!
You just go away
未来はいつも
The future is always
僕たちを待ってる
waiting for us.
大空駆けぬけて
Run through the vast sky,
海原越えて行け
cross the vast ocean and go!
天使の投げキッス
Catch an angel's
捕まえて!
blown kiss!
You can try!
飛び出そう 明日
Let's fly out toward tomorrow!
大地を踏みしめて
Step firmly on the earth,
君は目覚めていく
and you will wake up.
天使の微笑みで
With an angel's smile,
連れ出して
take me away!
終わらない冒険に出かけよう
Let's set off on an endless adventure,
いつまでも どこまでも
forever and ever!
流れ落ちる涙
The tears that stream down,
勇気に変えていく
I'll turn them into courage.
天使の羽広げ
Spreading angel wings,
舞い上がれ
soar high!
悲しみも痛みも包み込んで
Embracing both sadness and pain,
強くなれ
become stronger!
明日
Tomorrow!
大地を踏みしめて
Step firmly on the earth,
君は目覚めていく
and you will wake up.
天使の微笑みで
With an angel's smile,
連れ出して
take me away!
始まりはいつでも遅くないさ
It's never too late to start!
何度でも
No matter how many times,
no matter how many times,
何度でも 立ち上がれ
stand up again and again!
ファンサ
[Song: Fansa]
好きになって もっと
Love me even more!
私を見て もっと
Look at me even more!
恩返しは 愛のこもった投げキッスで
My repayment is a loving blown kiss!
気のせいじゃない 目は合ってるよ
It's not your imagination, our eyes really met!
ハート作って
Make a heart shape,
恋しちゃってください！
and please fall in love with me!
やれること何でもします
I'll do anything I can,
NGなしで
with no restrictions!
体当たり挑戦！
Giving it my absolute all!
ネットで見つけたあの子の目
The eyes of that girl I found on the internet,
「ふざけんな、誰より分かってる」し
saying "Don't mess with me, I know better than anyone else."
でも大丈夫、ここに立てば
But it's okay, if I stand here,
味方がいる (行くよ！)
I have allies! (Here I go!)
好きになって もっと
Love me even more!
私を見て もっと
Look at me even more!
恩返しは 愛のこもった投げキッスで
My repayment is a loving blown kiss!
虜にする もっと
I'll captivate you even more!
夢を見せる もっと
I'll show you dreams even more!
楽しんでってね 愛のこもったスペシャルナイト
So enjoy yourselves on this special night full of love!
ファンサしちゃうぞ
I'm gonna give you fanservice!
お手紙も書いてください
Please write letters to me too!
何度も読んで
I'll read them over and over,
宝物にします
and keep them as my treasures.
スキャンダルまだ早いけど
Though a scandal is still way too early,
裏切りません
I won't betray you!
宣言しときます
I'm declaring this right now!
強い嫌がらせには負けない
I won't lose to harsh harassment,
「ふざけんな、何倍も強くなってやる」
saying "Don't mess with me, I'll become many times stronger!"
だから辞めない
So I won't quit,
だって君がいる (行くよ！)
because you are here! (Here I go!)
拳上げて もっと
Raise your fists even higher!
汗をかいて もっと
Sweat even more!
恩返しは 愛のこもった脳内ビームで
My repayment is a loving brainwave beam!
大歓声 もっと
Cheers even louder!
まだまだね もっと
There's still more to go!
いけー
Go!
届いてね
I hope it reaches you...
愛のこもったわがままソング
...my selfish song filled with love!
ファンサしちゃうぞ
I'll give you some fan service!
お・わ・り・が・ち・か・づ・く・さ・び・し・い・ね
As the end approaches... I feel so lonely.
楽しそうなのに泣きそうだよ
Even though it's so fun, I'm about to cry.
次も 次も また会えるよね
We'll meet again next time, and the time after that, right?
約束！
Promise!
優しさに溢れている言葉も
Whether they are words overflowing with kindness...
心ない誰かの言葉さえも
...or even the thoughtless words of someone else,
必要なんだ 必要なんだ
I need them, I need them all.
強くなろう
I will become stronger!
好きに叫べ！もっと
Shout out as much as you want! More!
楽しんじゃえ！もっと
Just enjoy yourself! More!
忘れないで 特別な日になりますように
Don't forget this day, may it be a special one for you.
共に歌おう ずっと
Let's sing together, forever.
共に歩もう ずっと
Let's walk together, forever.
合言葉は とびきりの 「L・O・V・E」
Our password is an extra special "L-O-V-E"!
好きになって もっと
Fall in love with me even more!
私を見て もっと
Look at me even more!
恩返しは 愛のこもった投げキッスで
I'll return the favor with a loving blown kiss.
虜にする もっと
I'll captivate you even more!
夢を見せる もっと
I'll show you dreams even more!
楽しんでって 愛のこもったスペシャルな日と
Enjoy this special day packed with love, and...
ファンサしちゃうぞ
I'll give you some fan service!
ギターと孤独と蒼い惑星
[Guitar, Loneliness and Blue Planet]
突然降る夕立あらら 傘もないや嫌だ嫌だ
A sudden evening shower, oh my, no umbrella, I hate this so much!
空の機嫌なんか知らない
How should I know what mood the sky is in?
季節の変わり目の服は何着りゃいいんだ
What clothes am I even supposed to wear as seasons change?
春と秋とどこいっちゃったんだよ
Where on earth did spring and autumn go?
息もできない情報の圧力
The suffocating pressure of information overload...
めまいのらせんだ 私はどこにいる
It's a dizzying spiral, where even am I?
こんなにこんなに息の音尖らせるのに
Even though I make my breath sound so sharp like this,
変だね 世界の音がしない
How strange... the world is completely silent.
足りない足りない 誰にも気づかれない
It's not enough, not enough, no one ever notices me.
殴り書きみたいな音 出せない状態で叫んだよ
I screamed with a sound like scribbles, unable to bring it out.
ありのままなんて誰に見せるんだ
Who would I even show my true self to?
馬鹿な私は歌うだけ
Foolish as I am, I can only sing.
ぶちまけちゃおうか 星に
Should I just spill my guts out to the stars?
エリクサーに張り替える作業もなんとなくなんだ
Even restringing my guitar with Elixirs is just routine.
欠けた爪を少し触る
I gently touch my chipped fingernail.
半径300ミリの体で必死に鳴いてる
Screaming desperately within this body of a 300mm radius.
音楽にとっちゃここは地球だな
As far as music is concerned, this is Earth.
空気を吸い込んで空を殴るよ
Inhaling deeply, I take a swing at the sky.
何にも起きない私は無力さ
Nothing happens, I'm completely powerless.
だけどさ その手でこの弦を弾いたら
But still, if I pluck these strings with my own hands...
何かが変わって見えた
...it felt like something changed.
ような
Just maybe...
眩しい眩しいそんなに光るなよ
So dazzling, so bright, don't shine so much!
私のダサい影がより濃くなってしまうだろ
It only makes my pathetic shadow look even darker.
なんでこんなに熱くなっちゃってんだ 止まらない
Why am I getting so heated? I can't stop!
馬鹿な私は歌うだけ
Foolish as I am, I can only sing.
うるさいんだって心臓
Be quiet, my beating heart!
蒼い惑星 ひとりぼっちいっぱいの
On this blue planet, so full of lonely people...
音を聴いてきた
...I've been listening to the sounds.
回り続けて幾億年
Spinning on for hundreds of millions of years...
一瞬
...for just a fleeting moment.
変われない 嫌だ
I can't change, and I hate it!
聴いて 聴けよ
Listen! Listen to me!
私は 私は 私はここにいる
I am, I am, I am right here.
殴り書きみたいな音 出せない 情感だけじゃ足りないんだよ
I can't make a sound like a scribble, emotion alone isn't enough.
なんかになりたい なりたい なりたいものばかり
I want to be someone, I want to be, nothing but things I want to become...
だって
Because...
バカな私は歌うだけ
Foolish me, I just sing.
ぶちまけちゃおうか 星に
Should I pour it all out to the stars?
ハロンハワユ
[Song: Hello/How Are You]
ハロ
Hello
窓を開けて 小さく呟いた
I opened the window and whispered softly
ハワユ
How are you
誰もいない 部屋で一人
Alone in a room with no one else
モーニン
Morning
朝が来たよ 土砂降りの朝が
Morning has come, a pouring rainy morning
チクタク
Tick-tock
私のネジを 誰か巻いて
Will someone please wind my spring?
ららら...
La la la...
ハロ
Hello
昔のアニメに そんなのいたっけな
Was there a character like that in an old anime?
ハワユ
How are you
羨ましいな 皆に愛されて
I'm so jealous, being loved by everyone
スリーピン
Sleeping
バカなこと言ってないで 支度をしなくちゃ
Stop talking nonsense, I have to get ready
クライン
Crying
涙の跡を 隠すため
To hide the traces of my tears
もう 口癖になった「まぁいっか」
My habit has become saying, "Oh well..."
昨日の言葉がふと頭をよぎる
Yesterday's words suddenly cross my mind
「もう君には全然期待してないから」
"I'm not expecting anything from you anymore"
そりゃまぁ私だって 自分に期待などしてないけれど
Well, of course, even I don't expect anything from myself
アレは一体どういうつもりですか?
But what on earth did you mean by that?
喉まで出かかって 喉元につかえた言葉
The words that came up to my throat but got stuck
口を突いて出たのは嘘
And what slipped out of my mouth was a lie
こうして今日も私は貴重な
And so, today as well, I...
言葉を浪費して生きてゆく
...waste these precious words as I live on
なぜ隠してしまうのですか
Why do you end up hiding it?
笑われるのが怖いのですか
Are you afraid of being laughed at?
誰にも会いたくないのですか
Do you not want to see anyone?
それ本当に本当ですか
Is that really, truly true?
曖昧という名の海に溺れて
Drowning in a sea called ambiguity
息も出来ないほど苦しいの
It hurts so much I can't even breathe
少し声が聞きたくなりました
I've started to want to hear your voice a little
本当に弱いな
I'm really so weak
ハロ
Hello
一向に進まない支度の途中 朦朧とした頭で思う
In the middle of getting ready, making no progress, my hazy mind thinks...
「もう理由をつけて休んでしまおうかな」
"Maybe I should just make up an excuse and take the day off"
いやいや分かってますって 何となく言ってみただけだよ
No, no, I know, I just felt like saying it out loud
分かってるから怒らないでよ
I get it, so please don't get mad at me
幸せだろうと 不幸せだろうと
Whether you are happy or unhappy,
平等に残酷に朝日は昇る
cruelly and equally, the morning sun rises.
生きてくだけで精一杯の私に
To me, who is doing my absolute best just to live...
これ以上何を望むというの
...what more do you want me to ask for?
なぜ気に留めてしまうのですか
Why do you end up worrying about it?
本当は愛されたいのですか
Do you actually want to be loved?
その手を離したのは誰ですか
Who was the one that let go of that hand?
気が付いてますか
Have you realized it yet?
人生にタイムカードがあるなら
If life had a time card,
終わりの時間は何時なんだろう
I wonder when the clock-out time would be
私が生きた分の給料は 誰が払うのですか
Who is going to pay the wages for the life I've lived?
ハロ
Hello
サンキュー ありがとうって言いたいの
Thank you, I want to say thank you...
サンキュー ありがとうって言いたいよ
Thank you, I want to say thank you.
サンキュー 一度だけでもいいから
Thank you, even if it's just once...
心の底から大泣きしながら ありがとうって言いたいの
I want to cry from the bottom of my heart, and say thank you.
なぜ隠してしまうのですか？ 本当は聞いて欲しいのですか？
Why do you hide it away? Do you actually want to be heard?
絶対に笑ったりしないから 話してみませんか？
I'd never laugh at you, so won't you try talking to me?
口を開かなければわからない 思ってるだけでは伝わらない
No one will know unless you speak up; just thinking it won't get it across.
なんて面倒くさい生き物でしょう 人間というのは
What troublesome creatures humans are...
ハロー
Hello...
ハロー ハワユ
Hello, how are you?
あなたに ハロー
To you... Hello...
ハロー ハワユ
Hello, how are you?
you
[Song: you]
あなたは今どこで何をしていますか？
Where are you now, and what are you doing?
この空の続く場所にいますか？
Are you somewhere beneath this same sky?
今まで私の心を埋めていたモノ
The things that used to fill my heart...
失って初めて気付いた
...I only realized their worth once I lost them.
こんなにも私を支えてくれていたこと
Just how much you supported me...
こんなにも笑顔をくれていたこと
...and how much you made me smile.
失ってしまった代償は
The price of losing you...
とてつもなく大きすぎて
...is just far too great.
取り戻そうと必死に
Desperate to get you back,
手を伸ばしてもがくけれど
I reach out and struggle, but...
まるで風のようにすり抜けて
...you slip right through, just like the wind,
届きそうで届かない
so close, yet out of reach.
孤独と絶望に胸を締め付けられ
With loneliness and despair tightening around my chest,
心が壊れそうになるけれど
my heart feels like it's about to break...
思い出に残るあなたの笑顔が
But your smile that remains in my memories...
私をいつも励ましてくれる
...always encourages me.
もう一度あの頃に戻ろう
Let's return to those days once again.
今度はきっと大丈夫
This time, it will surely be alright.
いつもそばで笑っていよう
Let's always be smiling side by side...
あなたのすぐそばで...
...right next to you.
あなたは今どこで何をしていますか？
Where are you now, and what are you doing?
この空の続く場所にいますか？
Are you in a place where this sky continues?
いつものように笑顔でいてくれますか？
Will you keep smiling like you always do?
今はただそれを願い続ける...
Now, I will just keep wishing for that...
もうあなたから愛されることも
Now, neither being loved by you...
必要とされることもない
...nor being needed by you exists anymore.
そして私はこうして一人ぼっちで
And so, I am left all alone like this.
あの時あなたは何て言ったの？
What did you say to me back then?
届かない言葉は宙を舞う
My unreachable words dance in the air.
わかっているのに今日もまた
Even though I know this, today again...
叶わぬ願いごとを
...I make a wish that won't come true.
離さないで ぎゅっと
Don't let go, hold me tight.
手を握りしめて
Hold my hand tightly.
あなたと二人 ずっといたい
I want to be with you forever.
繋いだその手は温かくて
Our holding hands were so warm...
優しかった
...and so gentle.
あなたはいつもそうやって私を
You always did that, making me...
怒らせて最後には泣かすんだ
...angry, and in the end, making me cry.
だけど後になって
But later on...
ごめんねって言う
...you'd say, "I'm sorry."
その顔 好きだった
I loved that face of yours.
離さないで ぎゅっと
Don't let go, hold me tight.
そう思いきり
With all your might,
あなたの手を掴みに行きたい
I want to go grasp your hand.
抱きしめて
Embrace me...
おでこを合わせながら
...while our foreheads touch.
もう二度とは会えないってことを
Did you know that we would never meet again?
知っていたの？
Did you really know?
離さないで ぎゅっと
Don't let go, hold me tight,
あなたが好き
I love you.
もう一度だって
Won't you...
笑ってくれないの？
...smile for me just once more?
あなたの温もりが
Before your warmth...
消えちゃう前に
...fades away completely,
抱きしめて
...hold me tight.
[mumei]
[Title: mumei]
忘れてしまった
I only remember...
ことだけを覚えている
...the things I've forgotten.
ぽかりと空いた穴の先
At the end of the gaping hole...
偶然で君と出会った
I met you by chance
名前も 顔も 分からない君に
To you, whose name and face I didn't know
なんだか 懐かしいような気がした
I felt some strange sense of nostalgia
互いに 穴埋めてゆくように
As if we were filling each other's voids
ふざけ合って 笑い合って
Joking and laughing together
世界、あ、あ、あ、あ、愛のどこかにいる君のため
For you, who is somewhere in this world of love
今、あ、あ、あ、あ、生きているよ、僕ら
Right now, we are living
無名のまま
Remaining nameless
例えばこれが
For example, even if this is
映し出された幻でも
Just a projected illusion
確かに感じる
I can definitely feel
今君がそこにいること
That you are right there with me now
名前も顔もわからない君に
To you, whose name and face I don't know
さよならしてしまえば終わりだ
If we say goodbye, it all ends
君がいなきゃ穴は大きくなる
Without you, the void only grows larger
構わないさ
It doesn't matter
すぐ見つける
I'll find you right away
世界、あ、あ、あ、あ、愛のどこかにいる君はどこ
Where are you, who is somewhere in this world of love?
今、あ、あ、あ、あ、ここにいるよ、私
Right now, I am here
無名
Nameless
辺りは一面真っ暗な世界
All around is a pitch-black world
真っ逆さまに落ちてゆく
Falling headfirst into the abyss
無名だからこの世界には
Because I am nameless, in this world
忘れられ消えちゃうの
I'll be forgotten and fade away
それでも君が私求めるなら
But even so, if you search for me
この胸に開いた穴に今
Through the void opened in this chest, right now
君から私へと風が通り抜け
A breeze passes through from you to me
一羽の鳥が今君の元へと行く
A single bird now flies toward you
世界、あ、あ、あ、あ、愛のどこかにいる君のため
For you, who is somewhere in this world of love
今、あ、あ、あ、あ、生きていくよ、私
Right now, I will keep on living
無名のまま
Remaining nameless
Oh hi hoomans! Hoomansのみなさん、
Oh hi hoomans! Hello everyone,
Thank you so much for the last three and a half years. この3年半、最後まで支えてくれて本当にありがとうね。
Thank you so much for the last three and a half years. Thank you so much for supporting me until the end.
Even in writing, I know I won't be able to fully convey my feelings. 文章ではきっと、私の気持ちをすべて伝えきれないと思いますが、
Even in writing, I know I won't be able to fully convey my feelings. I know I won't be able to fully express all of my feelings in words, but...
本当にみなさんのおかげで、私の人生がとても豊かなものになりました。
ここから離れていっても、どんなことがあっても、みなさんのことを想っています。
You have truly changed my life for the better.
Wherever I go, no matter what I face, I will remember you!
みなさんがくれた優しさと支えは、
これからもずっと私の心の中にあります。
I will always carry the kindness and support
you showed me in my heart.
おかげさまで、想像以上のことがたくさんできました。
この気持ちは、一生忘れません。
I was able to do more than I ever imagined
because of you. I'll never forget this feeling!
私がhololiveにいたことが、誰かにとって少しでも力になれたなら、
誰かに笑顔を届けられたなら、
I hope that my presence in hololive was a good one.
生きていてよかったと心から思います。
それは私にとって、かけがえのない宝物です。
Any moment of joy I might have brought someone
makes me even happier to be alive!
一緒に過ごしてくれてありがとう。
Thank you for being here with me.
思いきりありのままの自分で楽しく
いられるあたたかい場所もくれてありがとう。
Thank you for giving me a warm space
to be silly and have fun.
そしてNanashi Mumeiでいさせてくれて、本当にありがとう。
Thank you for letting me be Nanashi Mumei.
Mumei